MATTEO OSIO

SENIOR DATA ENGINEER

matteo.osio1992@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/matteoosio/

With 9 years of experience covering user insights to technical platform development, I specialise in all aspects of data, from platform design to information modelling and analytics.

My work is driven by a commitment to innovation, decentralisation, and social impact. I value growth, opensource, and a curiosity in all my actions.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Data Warehousing ML and Operation research Data Analysis

Data Architecture Platform Engineering web3 technologies

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Global Algorithmic Tool Inbox. Designed and built the first operation research platform in HelloFresh SE following backend, frontend and data engineering best practices and standards. Platform is used across multiple markets with hundreds of active users on a daily basis.
- *Future Lab** on Sustainable Tourism. Personal success with *cocoex* we were able to engage 30 participants in a *Zukunftswerkstatt* methodology and bring the results to local public administrations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder, cocoex Nov 2021 - Present

- technology testing, and deepening expertise within the blockchain ecosystem for driving societal change through innovative solutions and DAO communities
- organise and manage Future Labs workshops while implementing futures techniques

Snr Data Engineer, HelloFresh SE

Jan 2023 - Present

- built and maintain a config based ingestion framework used for over 100 datasets in SCM domain
- Implemented multiple platform engineering best practices for cluster definition, maintenance and cost reductions

 ${\color{blue} \textbf{tech-stack: Airflow, AWS, CICD, Databricks, Docker, K8s, Python, REST API, Serverless, Snowflake, Spark and State of State of$

Data Engineer, HelloFresh SE

Jan 2019 - Jan 2023

- Cost of Goods Sold reporting serving 4 different department in SCM
- Data modernisation

tech-stack: Airflow, AWS, CICD, Postgres, Python, Spark, Tableau

BI Engineer, ICTeam (IT)

Jun 2016 - Jan 2019

• managed ETL processes and data visualisation to create reports supporting optical fiber placement analysis across Italy.

tech-stack: Microsoft SQL Server, Pentaho, QlikView

NoSQL Developer, MNE Creations! (PRC)

Jun 2015 - Oct 2015

• migration from relational database to document oriented database of gaming data tech-stack: Azure document oriented storage, C#, Postgres,

EDUCATION

Master BI & Big Data Analytics

2017 - 2018

University of Milan Bicocca

- master in Statistics
- thesis on "Physical Network Design with graph databases"

Bachelor of Business Informatics

2011 - 2015

University of Bergamo

• relevant courseworks in Structural Design and Project Management.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- languages: Italian (C2), English (C2), German (B1)
- certifications: Artificial Intelligence and Ethics (Computational Social Science Coursera)
- **presentations**: https://zukunftswerkstaetten.org/2023/10/27/das-war-das-zukunftswerkstatten-netzwerktreffen-2023/ Developing of future workshops on digital platforms
- interests: Music, Wine, Card Games and Sports